JOE: There are a range of different
initiatives, organisations and agencies
and companies that can help individuals
with autism into employment and some also
offer employment directly focusing on the
skills individuals with autism can offer.
BETH: 'The National Autistic Society'
provides resources and a variety of
work programmes, training and resources
for jobseekers with autism and can
help employers looking to benefit
from hiring a more diverse workforce.
JOE: ‘Ambitious about Autism’
is a national charity that has a
website covering a range of things
including getting into employment.
They run employability programmes
acting as a bridge to employment for
autistic people by removing barriers.
They work with employers giving them
access to talented and innovative
autistic employees and promote paid
work experience for individuals.
They also provide training
resources and mentorship.
BETH: ‘Auticon’ is an international
information technology consulting
firm company that exclusively
hires individuals with autism.
It employs their cognitive
diversity and specific talents to
supply services for many blue-chip
organisations throughout the world.
It embraces the extraordinary abilities
that individuals with autism can have and
their unique approach to problem solving.
JOE: The way individuals with high
functioning autism think can make
them more valued in the workplace,
and as companies can see the
opportunities to employ neuro-diverse
individuals, then this may help
others on the autistic spectrum.
BETH: Neuro-diverse people are wired
differently and can bring new perspectives
to a company and can make up for
the skills shortages in technology
companies and other digital industries.
JOE: More companies are looking to
recruit individuals who offer technical
talents and have attention to detail
and systematic approaches to tasks.
In a world that relies more on digital
development this can only expand further.